John Mellaley

Software developer

- johnmellaley@gmail.com
- https://johnmellaley.github.io/ MyProfile_Page/.
- 087 273 3822



About me

After many years working in master data and Procure to Pay, I decided to go back to my first passion coding. I am currently finishing a diploma is Software Development with Code institute to compliment my Bachelors in Commercial Computing. I am a conscientious selfstarter, with strong ability to prioritize effectively to accomplish multiple tasks and exceed targets.

Computer skills

HTML/CSS

JavaScript

Python

SQL/noSQL



Interests

Gardening

GAA

Politics

Education

Since October 2018

DIPLOMA - FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT

Code Institute Dublin

HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, GitHub, Heroku. JavaScript, Python, Flask, SQL\NoSQL

From September 1997 to June 2001

BSc in commercial computing (Hons)

Dundalk IT Dundalk, Ireland

C++, C, Java, Object-Oriented Programming.

From September 2013 to June 2014

Higher Diploma in Business in Finance National college of Ireland Dublin

Work experience

From 2019 to September 2019

Master Data Manager

Primark Dublin, Ireland

- Document the Finance Master Data process for migration and process for after go-live.
- Finance Data lead in Dress Rehearsals.

From October 2013 to September 2017

Procure to Pay Manger

MSD Global Financial Services Leopardstown, Dublin

- Delivered operational excellence by stabilizing the e-Invoicing solution and attained volume conversion of 70% of annual volume from paper to electronic invoicing.
- Created standard templates on metrics for both procurement and finance calls.
- Ensured that the current invoices on hold were consistently 90% for all markets.
- Managed business process outsource providers to agreed SLAs to ensure smooth running of operations.
- Delivered Compliant Operations and facilitated an effective Internal Control environment been maintained.

From October 2010 to October 2013

Vendor Master Lead

MSD Dublin, Ireland

 Provided and sustained high quality data in support for ERP Go Lives (EMEA), through participation in data migration, hyper care and sustainment activities leading to more successful go

lives.

- Supported the change management plan for transition from outsource provider, IBM to Genpact which entailed training the new Genpact team in India.
- Awarded recognition for customer service excellence and process improvement.

From September 2002 to August 2010

SAP Business Analyst (MM/SD)

Siemens Medical Solutions Diagnostics Europe Limited Swords, Dublin

- Supported material master team on Data migration project, resulting in over 30,000 materials to new SAP system
- Coordinated data cleansing, mapping of MM fields and data loading testing.
- Supported material master team on SAP implementation project which contributed to a more productive launch.
- Appointed material master expert responsible for SAP maintenance and processes that entail all aspects of data.
- Developed reports for the business and conduct data accuracy audits.